# **ELIUD NGORONGO**

KENYAN | 23 00614 | +254721503505 eliudnjenga@gmail.com| <u>LinkedIn</u> | <u>Portfolio</u>

#### **SUMMARY**

DevOps Engineer with a background in operations spanning over four years specializing in finding solutions through automation and CI/CD best practices to deliver excellent customer satisfaction by using cloud computing services. To achieve this, I rely on my commercial awareness and communication skills to deliver a robust experience to all teams across an organization which translates into a unique product experience delivered to consumers in every market space.

#### EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND

**Holberton - ALX**– Nairobi, Kenya

May, 2021 – August, 2022

Certificate in Software Engineering

November, 2021 – May, 2022

**Google Andela Dev Scholarship** – Nairobi, Kenya Certificate in Cloud Engineering

The University of Nairobi – Nairobi, Kenya

September, 2012 - May, 2016

BSc. Actuarial Science

#### PROFESSIONAL WORK EXPERIENCE

# **DevOps and Technical Support Engineer**

July 2022 - Present

WAYA MONEY-Accra, Ghana

- Configure and update new products on MongoDB and PostgreSQL using Table Plus for development and production.
- Design and implement automated SQL scripts to configure the PostgreSQL database by passing multiple values and populate it by looping through all entries reducing the delivery time of all related tasks by 90%.
- Maintain and regularly update Kubernetes clusters on GCP making sure the application never has downtime and managing lag when user traffic is high for better customer satisfaction.
- Test all APIs using Postman for all environments to ensure top-notch quality assurance resulting in a 5% increase in user satisfaction.
- On call responsibility in rotation with the engineering and customer service team enhancing collaboration and user experience.
- Conduct website performance tests to ensure 100% quality and zero defects.
- Collaborate with the front-end team to design web pages and applications that enhance UX/UI deliverables.

# **Commercial Operations Associate**

February 2022 - March 2022

KUNE FOODS LAB – Nairobi, Kenya

- Designed strategies for performing business analysis and associate initiatives for increase in profits by a margin of 29%.
- Developed business dashboard on monthly basis and prepare reports for management to highlight growth strategies enhancing efficiency company wide by 42%.

## Operations Team Member (part time) PEMARCRESS LTD – Nairobi, Kenya

June, 2019 – Present

- PEMARCRESS LID Namobi, Kenya
- Optimized internal processes and streamlined business functionality that resulted in a 48% expense decrease by the second year.
- Lead in partnership with Safaricom to introduce Bill Manager for a well-curated rent collection system that led to improved service delivery and quicker rent collection.

## **Operation Team Lead**

January, 2018 – December 2022

MARINA STORES - Nairobi, Kenya

• Installation, implementation, and maintenance of the Sage 50 ERP system and also trained my team to use it. This greatly reduced redundancies as well as grew the customer base. The debt owed to the business was reduced by 39%.

• Responsible for leading the sales, supply, and manufacturing teams with a total of 18 people.

### **SKILLS**

• Logistics • Python/Django/Flask • SQL

Leadership
C/Shell scripting
JavaScript/NodeJS/Java

• Commercial Awareness • HTML/CSS • GCP/AWS

#### **INTERESTS**

• Supply chain • Leadership • Gaming

# **PROJECTS**

• Printf – Prints output to display. • Shell – Linux CMD

• HbnB – Airbnb Clone